<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1' ?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
          "../../phpdoc/dtds/dbxml-4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
	 
<book>
 <title><literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal> - the MySQL Plugin code generator</title>

 <chapter>
  <title>Introduction</title>
  <section>
   <title>What is it?</title>
   <para>
    <literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal> is a tool that can automatically 
    create the basic framework for MySQL Plugin from a rather simple XML 
    specification file. The actual functionality is provided
    by the script <filename>mysql-plugin-gen</filename> that is installed by 
	the <literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal> package.
   </para>
   <para>
    The code generated by <filename>mysql-plugin-gen</filename> is designed 
    to work with MySQL versions 5.1 and above without modifications (although
    it is usually necessary to compile it for a specific server version).
   </para>
  </section>

  <section>
   <title>Features</title>
   <para>
    <literal>mysql-plugin-gen</literal> tries to support as many plugin 
    writing aspects as possible. This currently includes code generation 
    for fulltext parser plugins and preparation of 
	<filename>configure</filename> and <filename>Makefile</filename> 
	related build files.
   </para>
   <para>
    Support for pluggable storage engines is currently being worked on
    and user defined functions and other plugin types will be added 
    when these plugin types are supported by the MySQL server.
   </para>
  </section>

  <section>
   <title>Installation</title>
   <para>
	<literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal> is available in PEAR, the
    PHP Extension and Application Repository, on <literal>http://pear.php.net/</literal>.
   </para>

   <section>
    <title>Online installation</title>
    <para>
     Online installation using the PEAR installer is the easiest way 
     to install <literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal>, just issue the 
	 following command:
    </para>
    <programlisting>
pear install -o CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin
    </programlisting>
    <para>
     The PEAR installer will download and install the package itself
     and all packages that it depends on.
    </para>
   </section>

   <section>
    <title>Installing from package files</title>
    <para>
     When installing from package files downloaded from <literal>pear.php.net</literal>
     you have to resolve dependencies yourself. Currently <literal>CodeGen_PECL</literal>
     depends on two other PEAR packages: <literal>Console_Getopt</literal>, which is part
     of the PEAR base installation, <literal>CodeGen</literal>, the code generator
     base package, and <literal>CodeGen_MySQL</literal>, the base package for MySQL 
     specific code generators. You need to download all three packages for installation.
	 The actual installation is once again performed by the PEAR installer:
    </para>
    <programlisting>
pear install CogeGen-0.9.0.tgz
pear install CogeGen_MySQL-0.9.0.tgz
pear install CogeGen_MySQL-Plugin-0.9.0.tgz
    </programlisting>
   </section>

   <section>
    <title>Installing from PEAR CVS</title>
    <para>
     You can also install CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin snapshots from PEAR CVS. CVS snapshots may
     include features not yet available in any release package, but the code in
     CVS may not be as well tested as the release packages (or even broken at 
     times). Be warned, your milage may vary. Use the following sequence of 
     commands in your PEAR CVS checkout to install the latest
     <literal>CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin</literal> snapshot:
    </para>
    <programlisting>
cd pear
cd CodeGen
cvs update
pear install -f package.xml
cd ..
cd CodeGen_MySQL
cvs update
pear install -f package.xml
cd ..
cd CodeGen_MySQL_Plugin
cvs update
pear install -f package.xml
cd ..
    </programlisting>
   </section>
  </section>
 </chapter>

</book>